Guide to the Elsie H. Hillman Papers, 1920-2015 AIS.2013.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Campaigns, 1953-2013; II.
  - George H. W. Bush (For President) 1988, 1985-1989; 7.
    - Press Materials, Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Press Materials, Pennsylvania Campaign, Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Press Materials, State Committee Press Kit, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Press Releases, Talking Points on Senator Dan Quayle, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Press Releases and Press Updates, 1987-1988 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Quayle, Marilyn, Visit to Pittsburgh, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Report, Demographics of Targeted Counties, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Report, "Minimum Winning Coalition Analysis", 1987 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Republican Platform Booklet, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Riverboat Reception Proposal, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Rizzo, Frank, Letter to Voters, Drafts, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - RNC Opposition Research Booklet, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Senior Citizens for Bush, Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Speakers, Calendar and Surrogate Speaker Facts, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Speakers, Requests, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 14-16)
    - Speakers, Roster, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Speech Cards and Notes, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Speech Surrogates and Module Speeches, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Victory '88 Binder, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 20-21)
    - Victory '88 Budget and Staffing Binder, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Victory '88 Fundraising Event, Sample Invitation, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Voter Coalitions, Black Voters, Article Packets, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Voter Coalitions, Catholics for Bush, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Voter Coalitions, Drug-Free America, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Voter Coalitions, Hispanics for Bush, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Voter Coalitions, Labor Contact Lists, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Voter Coalitions, Lawyers for Bush, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Voter Coalitions, Women, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - George H. W. Bush (For President) 1992, 1990-1992; 8.
    Subseries 8 contains correspondence, memoranda, newspaper clippings, reports, and other records relating to Hillman's involvement in George H.W. Bush's campaign for reelection in 1992.
    - Allegheny County Volunteers and Candidates, Contact Lists, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Autumn Leaf Festival Appearance, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Bumper and Campaign Stickers, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Bush-Quayle '92 Spring Meeting, Minutes and Notes, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Campaign Staff Resumes, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Campaign Strategy Binder, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Citizens for Bush, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Congressional Meeting, Agenda, c. 1992 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Concordia Club, Speaking Engagement, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Copy of Campaign Strategy, "Mike Smith for Senate", 1991 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 20-28)
    - County Coordinators, Contact Lists, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 29)
    - Dispelling Myths of the Bush Record, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 30)
    - Duquesne Luncheon, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 31)
    - Electoral College, Notes, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 32)
    - Electoral System, Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 33)
    - Environmental Record, Newspaper Clippings and Reports, 1990-1992 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Finances, Expense list for "Victory '92" program, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Finances, Finance Meeting Minutes and Expense List, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Finances, National and State Finance Committees, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Finances, Regional Funding Goals and Fundraising Fact Sheets, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Fundraising Event Invitations, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Fundraising Meeting Minutes, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Gleason, Christopher, 1990-1991 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - GOP Riverfront Rally, Mailings and Flyers, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Handwritten Note on Bill Clinton, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Indiana County Lincoln Day Dinner, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Letters of Condolence upon Loss of Campaign, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - List of Retirements for the 1992 Election Cycle (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Mailings, Allegheny Conference on Community Development, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Mailings, Bush-Quayle Volunteers, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Mailings, Campaign Bulletins, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Mailings, Churches, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - Mailings, County Contacts, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Mailings, Drafts to members of Bush-Quayle Network, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Mailings, Ethnic Voters, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - Mailings, Mailing List for Announcement of Pennsylvania Bush Campaign, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - Mailings, Mailing List for Campaign Bulletins, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 22)
    - Mailings, Past Contributors, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 23)
    - Memoranda, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 24-29)
    - National Voter Coalition Rosters, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1990-1992 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Pennsylvania Campaign Leadership, County Contact Phone Lists, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Pennsylvania Campaign Leadership, Meeting Minutes and Planning Materials, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Pennsylvania Campaign Leadership, Targeted Counties and Delegation Profiles, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Pennsylvania Campaign Leadership Organization, Notes, 1991-1992 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Pennsylvania Campaign Map, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Pennsylvania Statewide Survey Results, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Pennsylvania Voter Coalition Leaders, Contact Lists, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Pittsburgh Luncheon, Fact Sheet, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Polling, Notes, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Polling, Proposed Poll, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Preliminary Campaign Organizational Notes, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Press Kit, County to County Media guide, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Press Kit, Fact Sheets, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Press Kit, Media Updates, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Press Kit, "President Bush on the Issues" Statements, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Press Kit, Speech Cards, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Press Kit, Speech Notes and Talking Points, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Press Release for Pennsylvania Bush-Quayle Leadership Announcement, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - Press Releases and Media Updates, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - Republican National Committee Northeast Regional Meeting, Agenda and Notes, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - Republican National Committee Northeast Regional Meeting, Communications Department Information, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - Republican National Committee Northeast Regional Meeting, Contact Lists, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - Republican National Committee Northeast Regional Meeting, Election Data, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 25)
    - Republican National Committee Northeast Regional Meeting, Minutes and Polling Data, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 26)
    - Republican National Committee Northeast Regional Meeting, Talking points, notes, and articles, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 27)
    - Republican National Convention Delegation, Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 40, Folder 28)
    - Republican National Convention Delegation, Delegate and Alternate Lists, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 29)
    - Republican National Convention Delegation, Delegate Correspondence and Profiles, 1991-1992 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Republican National Convention Delegation, Delegate Profile Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Republican National Convention Delegation, Delegate Selection Procedures, 1991-1992 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Republican National Convention Delegation, Delegate Totals and Delegates at Large Reports, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Republican National Convention Delegation, Memoranda, 1991-1992 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Republican National Convention Delegation, Notes and Reports, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Republican National Convention Delegation, Primary Candidate Withdrawal Form, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Republican State Committee, Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Satellite Program, Remarks by Richard Bond and Bob Teeter, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Script for Bush Event Co-Chaired by Pete Love, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Southwest Caucus, Meeting Minutes and Notes, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - State Campaign Leadership Directory, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - State Caucus Meetings, Agendas and Notes, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - State Caucus Meetings, Attendance Rosters, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - State Caucus Meetings, Memoranda, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - State Caucus Meetings, Travel Booking Materials, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - State Minimum Vote Analysis Report, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - State Party Building Program Guidelines, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - State Primaries, Notes, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - State Republicans for Clinton-Gore, List of Names, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - State Republicans for Clinton-Gore, Newspaper Clippings, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Statement of Support for Bush by Hillman, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - Visit by Governor Bill Weld, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - Voter Coalitions, African-Americans, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - Voter Coalitions, Croatian, 1991-1992 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - Voter Coalitions, Democrats for Bush, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - Voter Coalitions, General, 1991-1992 (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - Voter Coalitions, Gulf War Veterans, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - Voter Coalitions, Healthcare, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - Voter Coalitions, Jewish, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - Yeakel for Senate Campaign Information, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 31)
  - George W. Bush (For President) 2000, 1997-2001; 9.
    Subseries 9 contains correspondence, memoranda, mailings, newspaper clippings and other materials relating to Elsie Hillman's involvement in the Presidential Campaign of George W. Bush in 2000. Coming out of retirement, she took part in Bush's Presidential Exploratory Committee and helped to plan campaign events and visits of Bush family members including former First Lady Barbara Bush.
    - Announcement, Hillman to be Honorary State Chair of Presidential Exploratory Committee, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Biography of Governor George W. Bush, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Bush, Barbara, Brunch Event Planning Documents, 2000 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Bush, Barbara, Brunch Invitations, 2000 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Bush, Barbara, Brunch List of Key Contacts and Guest List, 2000 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Bush, Barbara, Magazine Article, 2000 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Bush Breakfast, Event Booking Notes and Invoices, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Bush Breakfast, Event Proposal and Planning Notes, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Bush, George H.W., Visit to Pennsylvania, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Campaign Bumper Stickers, Pamphlets, and Postcards, 1999-2000 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Campaign Updates, The Bush Report, 1999-2000 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Cleveland Committee on Foreign Relations, Military Trip Report, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Contribution Request Addresses, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - County Leadership Lists, c.1999 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Fundraising, Calendar of Events, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Fundraising, Guidelines and Rules, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - Fundraising, Mailing Instructions and Sample Letters, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - Fundraising, Presidential Exploratory Committee Fundraising Packet, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - Fundraising, Reception Event, Invitation, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - Fundraising, Sample Forms, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - GOP Debate, Excerpts, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - Governor Bush Luncheon, Resumes and Bios of Attendees, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - Inaugural Commemoratives Booklet, 2000-2001 (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - Inaugural Events, Baker Botts Open House Reception, Invitation, 2001 (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - Inaugural Events, Baker Botts Reception Honoring George H.W. Bush, Invitation, 2001 (Box 42, Folder 26)
    - Inaugural Events, Inaugural Salute to the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Invitation, 2001 (Box 42, Folder 27)
    - Inaugural Events, Republican Leadership Council Celebration, 2001 (Box 42, Folder 28)
    - Inaugural Events, Scheduling and Registration, 2000-2001 (Box 42, Folder 29)
    - Inauguration Ceremony Invitation, 2001 (Box 42, Folder 30)
    - McCain, John, 2000 (Box 42, Folder 31)
    - Memoranda, 1999-2000 (Box 42, Folder 32)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Magazine Articles, 1997-2000 (Box 43, Folder 1-4)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Magazine Articles, Women's Issues, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Non-Allocable Party Building Programs Guidelines, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Presidential Exploratory Committee, List of Contributors [incomplete], 1999 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Press Kit, Education Talking Points, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Press Kit, George W. Bush Speech Summary and Talking Points, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Press Kit, Social Security Talking Points, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Press Kit, Talking Points Packet, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - RNC Analysis of Speech by Gore, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Women's Committee for Finance, Contact List, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Women's Committee for Finance, List of Fundraising Events, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Women's Committee for Finance, Speeches by Bush on Key Issues, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - William W. Scranton (Pa Governor) 1962, 1962-1963; 10.
    Subseries 10 contains records related to Elsie Hillman's involvement in the 1962 Gubernatorial campaign of William Warren Scranton. Hillman, with the help of her friend and fellow party member, Wendell Freeland, helped to organize a rally at the Civic Arena in downtown Pittsburgh. The rally was a success, as indicated by a congratulatory telegram sent by Scranton. This subseries also contains an invitation and ticket to the Gubernatorial Inaugural Ball.
    - Inaugural Ball Invitation and Ticket, 1963 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1962-1963 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Rally at Civic Arena, Newspaper Clippings and Telegram of Congratulations from Scranton, 1962 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Richard Thornburgh (Pa Governor) 1978, 1977-1979; 11.
    Subseries 11 contains correspondence, notes, and other records related to Elsie Hillman's involvement in the 1978 Gubernatorial campaign of Richard L. Thornburgh. Hillman acted as co-chair of Thornburgh's primary campaign for governor, playing a key role in helping win him the candidacy and later the governorship.
    - Campaign Expenses, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - County Map and Primary Voting Totals, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Handwritten notes, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Hempfield Township Dinner Honoring Thornburgh, Program, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Inauguration Ceremony, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Memoranda and County Contact List, 1977-1978 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - H. John Heinz III (U. S. Congress) 1971, 12.
    Subseries 12 contains correspondence, press statements, newspaper clippings, and other records relating to Elsie Hillman's involvement in H. John Heinz III's campaign for U.S. Congress in 1971. Hillman chaired Labor for Heinz, and was successful in organizing and leveraging labor and union support for Heinz's Congressional Campaign.
    - Campaign Finances and Contributions, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Campaign Leaflets and Newsletters, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - List of Building Trades and Federal Regulation on Campaign Support, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Newsletters, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Political Climate Report for the 18th Congressional District, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Press Statements by Labor Leaders in Support of Heinz, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - Proposal for Role of the Candidate's Wife, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Telephone Survey for the 18th Congressional District, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - H. John Heinz III (U. S. Senate) 1982, 1977-1982; 13.
    Subseries 13 contains correspondence, media production, and speech notes relating to Elsie Hillman's involvement in H. John Heinz III's 1982 Senatorial Campaign. Hillman served on the state steering committee for Heinz for Senate. (Never a Spectator, 115)
    - Campaign Update and Planning Session Notes, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - John Heinz for Senate Committee, Media Production Costs, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - Nomination Speech delivered by Hillman to Republican State Committee of Pennsylvania, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Tom Ridge (Multiple Campaigns), 1982-1997; 14.
    Subseries 14 contains correspondence, newspaper clippings, planning documents, memoranda, and other records relating to Elsie Hillman's support in Tom Ridge's 1982 Congressional Campaign, as well as his 1994 and 1998 Gubernatorial Campaigns.
    - Congressional Campaign, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 24)
    - Congressional Campaign, Newspaper Clipping, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 25)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Breakfast for Tom Ridge, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 26)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Chester County Council of Republican Women, Speech notes, c.1993-1994 (Box 44, Folder 27)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 44, Folder 28)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, "Empowerment Projects" Packet, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 29)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, "First for Ridge" Lapel Pin Graphic, c. 1993 (Box 44, Folder 30)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Inaugural Committee Contributions Guide, 1998-1999 (Box 44, Folder 31)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Inaugural Events Committee List and Itinerary, 1994-1995 (Box 44, Folder 32)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Inaugural Gala Concert Planning Documents, 1994-1995 (Box 44, Folder 33)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Mailings, 1993-1994 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Memoranda, 1993-1994 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1993-1998 (Box 45, Folder 3-5)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Reception to Honor Governor-Elect Tom Ridge, List of Invitees, 1994 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Barbara Hafer (Multiple Campaigns), 1980-2006; 15.
    Subseries 15 contains correspondence, newspaper clippings, surveys, notes, and other records relating to Elsie Hillman's involvement in Barbara Hafer's numerous political campaigns. Much of the material covers her campaign for Allegheny County Commissioner in 1983, and for Governor in 1990. Also included are records related to her campaigns for State Treasurer in 1996, Lieutenant Governor in 1986, as well as Republican Party of Allegheny County Vice-Chair, and an exploratory campaign for Governor from 2001-2002.
    - County Commissioner Campaign, Budget Requirements, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - County Commissioner Campaign, Campaign Mailings, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - County Commissioner Campaign, Contact List, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - County Commissioner Campaign, Correspondence, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - County Commissioner Campaign, Letters from Elsie Hillman and Teresa Heinz in Support of Hafer, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - County Commissioner Campaign, List of County Appointments, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - County Commissioner Campaign, Memoranda, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - County Commissioner Campaign, Newspaper Clippings, 1983-1984 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - County Commissioner Campaign, Phone Messages, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - County Commissioner Campaign, Press Material, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - County Commissioner Campaign, Promissory Note to Hafer Campaign, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Exploratory Gubernatorial Campaign, 2001-2002 (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Campaign Planning Notes, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, County Coordinators Phone List, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Fundraising Event Guide, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Guest List for Hafer Reception, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Hafer Finance Plan Notes, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, List of Key Contacts, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Lutherans Jail Roth Press Release, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Memoranda, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Newspaper Articles and Magazine Clippings, 1989-1990 (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Republican Primary Leadership Committee, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 29)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, Statement of Elsie Hillman in support of Hafer, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 30)
    - Lieutenant Gubernatorial Campaign, Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1985-1986 (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - Lieutenant Gubernatorial Campaign, Survey Results, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 32)
    - Republican Committee of Allegheny County Vice-Chair Campaign, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 33)
    - State Treasurer Campaign, 1996 (Box 45, Folder 34)
  - Elmer McClung (Pittsburgh City Council) 1986, 1985-1986; 16.
    Subseries 16 contains correspondence, newspaper clippings, notes, and other records relating to Elsie Hillman's interest and involvement in the campaign of Elmer McClung for Pittsburgh City council in 1986. When the city Democratic Party failed to produce any African-American candidates, Elsie pushed for McClung, an African-American Republican from East Liberty, to be a candidate on the Republican ticket.
    - 1985 Republican City Platform (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Candidate Resume, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Handwritten Notes, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Media Campaign Budget and Press Release Draft, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1985-1986 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Various Campaigns, 1966-2013; 17.
    Subseries 17 contains records relating to campaigns in which Elsie Hillman either had interest in or was actively involved in. These include various mayoral, gubernatorial, congressional, as well as campaigns for Pittsburgh City Council, County Executive, and judicial posts. Also in this subseries is a list of contributions made to both the campaigns of Tom Ridge and Barbara Hafer.
    - Allegheny County Court of Common Pleas, 2013 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Atkinson, Eugene (US Congress), Correspondence and Memoranda, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Atkinson, Eugene (US Congress), Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Baker, Howard (Presidential), 1979-1980 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Clinger, Bill (US Congress), 1985 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Cossetti, Joseph (Pittsburgh Mayoral), 1977 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Dole, Robert (Presidential), Newspaper Clippings, 1996 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Dole, Robert (Presidential), Thank You Card Signed by Phone Bank Workers, 1996 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Fleck, Dan (County Commissioner), 1991 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Holtzman, Marc (US Congress), Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Holtzman, Marc (US Congress), Mailings, 1985-1986 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Holtzman, Marc (US Congress), Press, 1984-1986 (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Hunt, William R. (County Commissioner), Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 46, Folder 19)